JC Coles

(661) 319-2747 | jcoles1155@gmail.com | Ventura, CA | https://github.com/jcoles1155 https://jctech.blog/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholas-jc-coles-314495a6/

Full Stack Developer

Full Stack Web developer with a passion for creating great products. My experience in many different work environments has taught me to adapt quickly to new technologies and tasks. As a strong IT professional, I'm excited to apply my insights with a team of other great engineers and to grow within a dynamic company.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Python, SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, SASS

TECHNOLOGIES: MERN, LAMP, Node.js, MongoDB, Linux/Unix, React.js, Express.js, Postgres, Django, Laravel, Bootstrap, JQuery, Oauth, JWT, Github, Heroku, Insomnia, Passport, Morgan, bcrypt, Microsoft Office Suite, Wordpress, Squarespace

PROJECTS

https://gig-board.herokuapp.com/

- Job board app built with React on a team of 5 other classmates with the MERN stack
- Used Github heavily to communicate with teammates and create issues within the project panel
- Used Heroku to deploy and MongoDB atlas to manage database

https://jcoles1155.github.io/GOPS/index.html

- Card game built with vanilla javascript using basic DOM manipulation techniques
- Used Javascript and JQuery to create dynamically loading pages that presented an updated score
- Applied Git throughout the process for version control and tested features

https://arcane-tundra-61980.herokuapp.com/

- Beer Recipe app where users can keep a list of recipes they've created and browse recipes from other users
- Implemented authentication with sign up / log in / log out functions using Passport.js and OAuth
- App built with full CRUD using Express and a MongoDB database using mongoose
- Used Heroku to deploy and MongoDB atlas to manage database

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Surfline Corporation – Network Technician (Ventura, CA)

February 2018 – Present

- Install cameras and routers when needed from Santa Barbra to Oxnard California
- Provide first point of contact for customers with cameras, acknowledged client and addressed needs
- Troubleshot equipment in my region during connection outages and network failures

Coles Carbide Corporation – Office Administrator, Machinist (Bakersfield, CA)

August 2017 - Present

- Operate 3-axis CNC lathes to retool other machines, and makes cuts on parts
- Managed the implementation of the inventory and warehouse management systems and software
- Operate precision metalworking and laser etching machinery

Madewest Brewing Company – Cellar Person (Ventura, CA)

December 2019 – August 2020

- Facilitated cellar operations daily in preparation for and during brews
- Managed the dry hopping schedule for core beers and logged gravity levels of all beers daily
- Operated forklift in order to store, pack, and ship beers with Stone Distribution

EDUCATION

General Assembly: Software Engineering Immersive, (MERN stack, Javascript, Python)

Oct 2020 – May 2021

Jan 2016 - June 2018

Ventura College: General Education